I think it was the 27th of Shahrivar
when the pager explosion incident happened.
Were you in Beirut? Yes.
What's your story from that day?
I mean, what did you see?
Perhaps one of the most bitter memories, truly,
etched in my mind, was the pager incident.
Because that very day coincided with our last meeting
with Seyed Hashem.
And quite coincidentally, we hadn't seen him for a long time.
Due to various incidents, it wasn't possible for him to travel.
The opportunity for us to gather as a family was very limited.
And by chance, that day we were supposed to
have a family lunch, all gathered together,
and he was also supposed to come for us to see him.
Well, as I recall, it was exactly noon
when the pager incident happened. Because we were all at the dining table
and had just laid out the food to start.
Suddenly, a very terrifying sound...
I mean, the sound was very loud,
and at the same time, a strange smoke and dust
entered the house.
And well, we didn't know what it was, or what had happened.
At first, we thought maybe a gas canister or something had exploded downstairs.
Because in the hours prior, nothing specific had happened
to make us think that something might occur that day.
Then we saw, no, the noise in the street
started to grow, and people were shouting,
and there were some strange and unusual sounds.
We got a little worried and curious. After a few minutes,
we realized that a number of pagers carried by our loved ones and the security team had exploded.
So, your first encounter
was with the pager incident. Truly, I think
for up to an hour after the incident,
no one had figured it out yet.
I mean, they realized that many communication devices had exploded,
but they didn't know they were all related just to the pagers.
They didn't know if it was just pagers in some cases
or if other devices were involved too.
And in those first moments, you probably thought it was just
something related to the security team. We thought that
an assassination attempt
was about to happen. And, due to various scenarios, the security team's immediate assessment was that...
they might have created a diversion to draw him out, and during the evacuation, while he was in the building, they would target the car.
And, the scenarios that were really going through our minds at that moment,
we truly didn't understand what had happened.
Until some calls were made,
and we were informed that a large number of pagers...
And when they saw what had exploded in the guards' room
and what had happened, they realized that
the pagers carried by the security teams had exploded.
What was Seyed Hashem's own reaction in those moments?
Very calm.
I mean, when I say very calm,
truly, both in his expression, and I could tell
from his demeanor, he was just a very calm and patient person by nature.
And in that situation, our only concern was him.
We didn't know the source of the incident or what was happening,
and we were worried for his life.
I kept insisting to him that,
'You shouldn't stay here.'
Maybe another incident is about to happen, and it could be very dangerous for you to stay.
He kept squeezing my hand, saying,
'Be calm. We don't know what's happened yet,
and we need to decide with a clear head.
If we act out of worry and anxiety, we might make the wrong decision.'
And I remember we had set the dinner table...
He looked at us... we hadn't even touched the food when it happened.
And he told us, 'Sit down, have a few bites of food until we see what's happened.'
But there was so much anxiety and stress
that no one could even sit down.
He was mostly trying to calm us
so that we could be calm, allowing them to make the right decision.